Here's how I would figure out whether this division of cookies is within
以下是我判断 cookie 划分是否在
what I expected.
我预期之内的方法
I have a random event with exactly two outcomes.
我有个随机事件 恰好有两个结果
A cookie gets assigned to either the control or the experiment group.
一个 cookie 要么被分配到对照组 要么到实验组
I can think of this as like flipping a fair coin and
我认为这就像掷硬币般公平
if the coin comes up heads, I'll put the cookie in the control group.
如果硬币的正面朝上 我就会把 cookie 放在对照组
Then I want to know if it's surprising that the coin came up heads 64,454
接下来我想知道的是 如果硬币的正面朝上了
times.
64,454 次 这是否奇怪
Does that sound familiar?
这是否听起来很熟悉
The number of heads will follow the binomial distribution, so
正面的次数遵循二项分布定理 所以
I can construct a binomial confidence interval like in lesson one.
我可以构建一个类似第一课中的二项式置信区间
The total sample size here is about 120,000,
本次 样本总量大约是 12 万
which is definitely enough to assume a normal distribution.
这对假设一个正态分布来说足够了
So here are the steps I'll take.
以下是详细步骤
First, I'll compute the standard deviation of a binomial distribution
首先 我会计算二项分布的标准差
with probability 0.5 of success,
成功率为 0.5
which I'll define as being assigned to the control group.
我规定它被分配到对照组
Then I'll multiply the standard deviation by the z-score
然后我用标准差乘以置信度的 z 值
of my confidence level to get the margin of error,
得到误差范围
then I'll compute a confidence interval around 0.5.
接着我会计算一个 0.5 左右的置信区间
If the experiment is setup properly,
如果实验设置合理
it's very likely that thee observed fraction of successes or
观察到的成功率或
cookies in the control group will fall within this confidence interval.
对照组的 cookie 很有可能落入置信区间
And finally, I'll compute thee observed fraction of successes or
最后 我会计算观察到的成功率 或
cookies in the control group and
对照组的 cookie
I'll check whether this value falls with in this confidence interval.
我还会检查这个值是否落入置信区间
This is a little different then thee approach in lesson one, where we
这和第一课中的方法略有不同
computed the confidence interval around the observed click-through probability.
第一课中我们计算观察到的点击概率周围的置信区间
In that case, we didn't know the true click-through probability.
那个例子中 我们不知道真实的点击概率
But here, I know that if the experiment is set up properly,
但这里 我知道实验是否设置合理
the true probability is 0.5.
真实的概率是 0.5
So, I can compute that confidence interval.
所以 我可以计算置信区间
The results are the same though.
但结果一样
Now, I'll go through these steps for this data.
现在 我以此数据为例 操作这些步骤
The standard deviation comes to 0.0014.
标准差是 0.0014
I'll use a 95% confidence level as usual, so the z-score is 1.96.
置信度我按例取 95% 则 z 值是1.96
So the margin of error comes to 0.0027.
所以误差范围是 0.0027
That means that the confidence interval goes from 0.4973 to 0.5027.
这意味着置信区间为 0.4973 至 0.5027
So 95% of the time,
所以 95% 的概率
the observed fraction of cookies should fall within this range.
观察到的 cookie 数量会落在该范围
In fact, the fraction of cookies in the control group,
实际上 对照组中 cookie 数量
which I'll p hat is 0.5104.
我用 p? 来表示 是 0.5104
Now this is significantly greater than 0.5027, so
很明显超过了 0.5027
something about this setup is incorrect.
所以设置有点问题
To get a better idea of what could be going wrong,
为了更好地查明哪里出了问题
it's a good idea to look at the day by day data again.
最好再看一遍每日数据
One good thing to check is whether any particular day stands out as
检查的一个好处是可以看出是由于某天的数据异常导致该问题
causing the problem or whether it seems to be an overall pattern.
还是整体模式出了问题
First, I'll look at which specific days had more cookies in the control group.
首先 我会查看对照组中的 cookie 哪几天较多
It turns out that in 11 out of 14 days, there were more cookies in the control
结果显示 14 天中有 11 天 对照组的 cookie 都较多
group than the experiment, which is quite high.
与实验组相比 相当高
I'll also compute the fraction of the cookies that were in the control group
我也会计算对照组每天的 cookie 数量
each day, there were a few days with 0.53 or higher.
有几天是 0.53 甚至更高
And no day obviously stands out as the highest.
没有哪一天是明显最异常的
This points to an overall problem rather than a problem on a specific day.
这表明是总体模式的问题而非具体某一天的问题
At this point, it's a good idea to talk to the engineers and
事已至此 告诉工程师
figure out if something was wrong with the experiment setup.
查明实验设置是否有问题 是个不错的主意
If that doesn't work, you could try slicing.
如果没用 你可以尝试进行分割
For example, by country, language or
比如 以国家、语言 或
platform to see if one particular slice looks like it's causing the problem or
平台为标准进行分割 看是哪个部分可能造成该问题
you could check the age of the cookies in each group.
或者你可以查看各组中 cookie 的龄长
Does one group tend to have more new cookies while the other group has older
看是否一组常有新 cookie 而另一组有旧 cookie
cookies or something like that.
或其他类似这样的事情
Now suppose you run another experiment, this time for
现在假定你运行另一个实验
seven days with event based diversion.
这次为 7 天 以事件为分组标准
This table shows the number of pageviews in the control and
该表显示每天对照组和
experiment groups each day.
实验组的页面浏览量
The total number of events in the control and
对照组和实验组的事件总数
experiment groups are these numbers.
是这些数字
Calculate a 95% confidence interval for the fraction of total pageviews in
按 95% 的置信区间计算对照组页面浏览总量
the control group and put your bounds in these boxes to four decimal places.
把范围填在这这些方框中 精确到小数点后四位
The center of your confidence interval should be 0.5,
置信区间的中心应为 0.5
then calculate the observed fraction of pageviews in the control group and
然后计算观察到的对照组页面浏览量
write the answer in this box.
将结果填在这个方框里
Also, to four decimal places.
同样精确到小数点后四位
Does this distribution between the control and
对照组和实验组之间的分布
experiment group pass your sanity check?
通过你的完整性检查了吗
Select yes or no.
选择 是 或 否